# LYDIA BALASINGH

+91-9945101623 | <u>lydibsingh@gmail.com</u>

# Front-End Developer/Visual Designer

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Close to 12 years of experience in Front-End/UI Design & Development along with Visual/Graphic Designing Skills. I have working experience in creating Rapid Prototyping/HTML layouts using Figma/Sketch/Bootstrap/WordPress. Having excellent collaboration with other team members & stakeholders, I have worked with multiple clients across different domains.

# **TOOLS & TECHNOLOGY**

- HTML5/CSS3
- Bootstrap4/5
- WordPress5/Drupal8
- Adobe CC (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Animate)
- Pixelmator/AutoDesk Graphic
- Sketch/Figma/Adobe XD

#### **GET-IN-TOUCH**

Mobile : +91-9945101623

Email : lydibsingh@gmail.com

**LinkedIn**: lydia-balasingh **Portfolio**: <u>haidyl.github.io</u>

#### **EDUCATION**

-> MCA from Bharathiar University (Karunya Institute of Technology)

#### **CERTIFICATE COURSES**

- -> Web-Centric Computing from NIIT
- -> Virtual Reality from UGC
- -> Magic Multimedia from Bi-Tech
- -> Agile Software Development from Coursera
- -> Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

## WEBSITES/WIREFRAMES

https://www.atricure.com

https://azurehpc-certification.github.io

https://www.actagainstafib.com

http://www.csidivyashanthichurch.neth

https://bit.ly/3R9XqPz

https://bit.ly/3Pm6TZr

https://bit.ly/3044h6Q

https://bit.ly/3030PCk

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Capgemini Technology Services India Ltd., Bengaluru as Senior Consultant |

Project Lead in Front-End Design (19-Feb-2018 to till date)

Currently working for Microsoft Client. Also find below my roles and responsibilities in the current project:

# Various Projects handled within Capgemini

1. Type of Industry: Finance (Microsoft)

Project Description: Recreate an all new UX Design for the existing reporting

website. Modernization of Data Visualization in every aspect.

Role/Title: Lead - UX Designer
Project Duration: Apr 2022 - Till Date

Responsibilities:

→ Working with the customer end-end from initial requirements

- → Conduct competitive analyses of other websites that operate in the same space
- → Prepare and present rough drafts to internal teams and key stakeholders
- → Develop quick mockups for our development and design team
- → Track usability goals and prepare reports for senior management
- → Coordinate with UI design team

Operating Systems / Software / Languages: Windows, HTML 5, CSS3, Adobe

Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Pixlr (Online Graphic Editor)

Special Tools: Wireframing & UI Design (Figma)

2. Type of Industry: Microsoft Azure Technology (Microsoft)

**Project Description:** Creation of a static Landing Page which promotes different ISVs of the Microsoft Azure Platform Model. The major task is to convert the normal Word Documentations to creative & interactive HTML Pages.

Role/Title: Module Lead, UI/UX Designer, Word expert (HTML/CSS/Word)

Project Duration: Nov 2021 - Till Date

#### Responsibilities:

- → Creation of quick Landing pages for GitHub
- → Worked on Mobile Frist Bootstrap Layouts for UI Design.
- → Provide support to the customer during UAT and post production support as part of maintenance
- → Handling Wireframes/Prototypes for the proposed Uls.
- → Worked on Images and Icon creation wherever required to customize the Landing page.
- → Worked on CSS Framework (Bootstrap 4/5) and HTML5 /CSS3
- → Rapid conversion of Word Document to HTML pages in modern UI format

**Operating Systems/ Software / Languages:** Windows, SharePoint, HTML 5, CSS3, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Pixlr (Online Graphic Editor)

Special Tools: Wireframing & UI Design (Figma)

3. Type of Industry: Learning & Development

**Project Description:** Creation of a completely new UI for an existing internal webpage in terms of Learning & Development. This Project gives the End User a completely new look & feel of the functionalities related to the Skills, Learnings & Certifications related to the Employees within the Organization Globally according to their Grades & Roles.

**Role/Title:** Project Manager / UI/UX Designer (SharePoint Platform - Capgemini)

Project Duration: July 2021 - Nov 2021

**Responsibilities:** End-to-end Project Management as a Scrum Master. Handled the entire project from start to finish (including the Stakeholders requirements to delivery). Along with the Project deliverables, I have taken up the UI Designer role in the project (Complete UI Layout design of the project).

- → Creating project UI Layout for further SharePoint Development
- → Project Goal setting | Tracking | Timelines
- → Regular Documentation of every single task and updating the same in DevOps tools.
- → Handling project correspondence at all levels
- → Worked on Images and HTML/CSS wherever required to customize the SharePoint Modern Pages.
- → Worked in complete Agile Methodology with multiple sprints.

**Operating Systems/ Software / Languages:** Windows, SharePoint, HTML 5, CSS3, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Pixlr (Online Editor)

Special Tools: Wireframing & UI Design (Figma)

4. Type of Industry: Healthcare (AtriCure)

**Project Description:** Content management of multiple client websites related to Healthcare. Develop and maintain two-three websites related to the client requirements. (WordPress/Drupal)

Role/Title: Module Lead / Frond-End Design (Content Management System)

Project Duration: April 2019 - Jun 2021

Responsibilities:

- → Handling an entire Sub-Project (https://www.actagainstafib.com) in CMS (WordPress 5)
- → Working on a major Module Contact Us page with (Gravity Forms)
- → Creating new UI Design with latest Bootstrapping for (https://www.atricure.com/)
- → Delivered 200+ User Stories with 95% On Time Delivery
- → Regular Documentation of every single task and updating the same in DevOps tools
- → Handling end to end projects along with latest CMS tools and Front-End Frameworks
- → Coordinate with the Customer and the Onsite counterpart for requirements, Project Estimation and Delivery
- → Working in Agile Methodology
- → Handling project correspondence at all levels
- → Working on Images and Graphics as and when required in the Project accomplishments for each position

**Operating Systems / Software / Languages:** Windows & Mac, WordPress 5, Drupal 8, Bootstrap 4, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery, HTML 5, CSS3

**Special Tools:** Wireframing (Figma, Zeplin, Sketch, Wireframe CC)

5. Type of Industry: Content Management / Document Management (HP)

**Project Description:** The HP BI Factory held an existing CMS Web content called Confluence for which a new alternative Creative Web layout was proposed.

**Phase I:** Wire-framing of the newly proposed Layout

**Phase II:** UI Designing for the approved wire-framing using Bootstrap. **Phase III:** Implementation of the UI Design to a new CMS Tool (WordPress)

Role/Title: GUI Designer / HP BI Factory (UI Designing and CMS)

Project Duration: January 2019 - February 2019

Responsibilities:

- → Detailed review on the existing CMS Tool (Confluence).
- → Creating new Wireframes/Prototypes for the proposed UI.
- → Creating Bootstrap Layouts for HP BI Factory UI Design.
- → Implementation of UI Design in CMS (WordPress).
- → Creating various Icons, Flash GIFs for the Graphical presentations.
- Creating PowerPoint slides for the project presentations all through the course of the project.

Operating Systems / Software / Languages: Windows 10, Adobe CC, Bootstrap

Special Tools: Wireframe CC, WordPress

6. Type of Industry: FMCG (P&G)

**Project Description:** 

**Module I:** Automated font conversion process – To convert the User Inputted Fonts to its relevant substituted Font which is available in the Client's Font Server.

**Module II**: Image Flattening of Multiple Creative – To flatten the layers of the input files (Adobe Illustrator format) to just 2 layers (Text and Background)

Role/Title: Project Lead / Adobe Illustrator-Visualization (Font Scripting & Image Flattening)

Project Duration: February 2018 - June 2018

Responsibilities:

- → Worked on Automation of Font Scripting and Image Flattening.
- → Reviewing the process of Font Conversion Scripting

- → Handling project correspondence at all levels
- → Team Co-ordination

Operating Systems / Software / Languages: Windows 10, Adobe Illustrator CC 2017

Special Tools: Adobe Scripting

#### **Other Work Experiences**

Zopsmart Technology Pvt., Ltd., (Zopnow) Bengaluru as *Sr. Graphic Designer in Digital Marketing & Design* (06-Oct-2014 to 31-Jul-2017)

Lead Designer in creating Product Promo Pages, Hoardings and Posters, Website Banners, Mailers, Website layouts, Flex Banners, E-Magazine & Print Magazine, Image Editing, Blogs, Offline Printing. Training Junior Designers in Print/ Social Media and Photo Editing.

# Suksh Technology Pvt., Ltd., Bengaluru as Sr. Graphic/Web Designer (15-Jun-2012 to 25-Apr-2014)

Working in E-Commerce Platform was a new eye opener to my career. (Handling Websites, E-Mailers, Google Ads, Promotions, Flash Ads, Website Layout designs)

#### Kairos Multimedia Pvt., Ltd., New Delhi as Head-Web Designing

(01-Apr-2011 to 31-Mar-2012)

Managed a team of web designers in various overseas Web Projects at various levels. Handled End-End Project Management including (Data collection, PowerPoint/Flash presentations and reviews.)

The Good Samaritans (NGO), New Delhi as SW Programmer/HR Assistant (29-Nov-2004 to 29-Apr-2006)

Started my career as a Software Programmer in an NGO gaining lots of experience. It was a dual role. (Developing Software + HR Management)

### **KEY SKILLS**

**Functional:** UI/UX Designing, Wireframes, Responsive Webpage layouts using HTML5/CSS3, WordPress 5 / Drupal 8 Theming, HTML/CSS e-mailer & web templates, Posters, Hoardings, Banners, Blogs, Logos/Branding, Offline Printing & Flash Ads, Adobe Illustrator Scripting & Automation, Module Lead, Team Building, Team Leader, Customer Relationship, Design/Development, Documentation, Excellent communication and interpretation skills, Azure DevOps, GIT, Agile Methodology. Managing deliverable end to end, along with leading the project by reviewing and testing at all levels.

**Technical:** HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4/5, WordPress 5, Drupal 8, SharePoint (Modern Pages), Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Animate. XD), Figma, Zeplin, Wireframe CC, JavaScript & jQuery (basic knowledge)

# **FEATURED IN**

- → Professional experience working on commercial software products
- → Proficient in rapid web markups HTML5/CSS3, including CSS3 with latest Bootstrap Framework
- → Perusing knowledge in latest React JS (Redux)
- → Good understanding of server-side CSS pre-processing platform (SASS)
- → Actively handled Blogs, social media Pages, HTML Mailer Templates
- → Heading E-Magazines / Offline Printing, Posters
- → Good understanding of SEO principles

- → Conversion of the Word Documentations to creative & interactive HTML Pages
- → Good Knowledge of color rendering
- → Building reusable code and libraries for future use
- → Worked on project executed on Agile Methodology
- → Proficient understanding of code versioning tools, (Git, Azure DevOps)
- → Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders
- → Experience in build/lead teams
- → Effective oral and written communication skills